hi there so this is a glass bead game
ten minutes thirty second turn so ten
thirty second turns per player in
sequence the topic is conspiracy I
apologize for the intrusiveness of the
time we're trying to figure out a better
way of having a timer on screen that
doesn't take up the whole bloody screen
but in the meantime you can see the
players in thumbnails and yeah I hope
you enjoy it I thought this is a pretty
fun game conspiracy to breathe together
to control the oxygen in the room
collectively breathe in see and in so
doing control the flow of combustion who
controls the oxygen in the room how many
people breathe together mmm half the
hungriest lungs conspiracy is collective
but it is also secretive so it is not
universally collective it's an in-group
out-group situation so you have one in
group seeking to steal all the oxygen
from itself
breathing collectively before everybody
else is able to breathe and get their
bit of oxygen the beauty of conspiracy
is that it is invisible we can be
breathing at the same time we can be
breathing together and nobody can notice
it because we have breathed together
behind closed door falls where
conspiracies are born and then
afterwards wherever we go we always
breathe together our breath is always in
synced con
soyal behind closed doors is evokes
notions of whispering and furtive
glances there's something in a
conspiracy where the conspirators
there's shame somehow in there they know
they're doing wrong they know they have
to look over their shoulder and make
sure nobody else can figure out what
they're doing
shei in fear pride passwords secret
handshakes secret meeting locations
drawer a symbol on the floor in chalk as
we meet and then wipe it away a hand up
hand on a table and we can speak hand
down terms that is no longer safe safety
is key the fear of exposure is the is
the deepest fear of the conspirator as
exposure must be avoided at all costs
fearful of the light lurking skulking in
shadows never able to emerge into the
light for fear of others seeing what you
are up to seeing that you are working
against them if the conspiration is
revealed then it breaks the potency of
the accumulated collective breath it is
only when the ritual is completed that
the conspiracy can burst forth into the
world and upturn the existing order the
power of the collective wind only when
it is too late to do anything about it
and the conspiracy reveal itself
at which point if successful it is no
longer a conspiracy but the new normal
it as user to normality conspiracy has
become today
all normals are conspiracies some
conspiracies are more consensual than
others some conspiracies we have
forgotten that they are conspiracies and
we accept them as the order of the
communal breath but this is how
everybody should breathe that some
should breathe deeply and others breathe
shallowly a conspiracy that is so
ancient and so widespread that is no
longer thought of as a conspiracy so is
at what point does a conspiracy stop
being a conspiracy so number one when it
is revealed and number two when it is
what the dominant the majority the
significant minority and the spirity is
a natural component of the collective
trance
the problem is non-consensual conspiracy
where the conspiracy is obfuscated is
hidden through various means to prevent
the collectives adaptation of the
conspiracy to the fluctuations of the
world of oh it's really interesting so a
conspiracy
although when first hatched may be
powerful and adaptive because it must
take place behind closed doors and
because it can only be participated in
by a few people
it is unresponsive to change it and by
the time it is revealed it may no longer
be functional small conspiracies the
benefit few people a global conspiracy
of everybody breathing simultaneously
towards one goal
all trying to help each other take the
deepest breath to achieve the fullest
flow of blood throughout the whole body
global conspiracy a global conspiracy
would be a global collaboration there is
no difference with no longer leaving
anybody out it has had the light shone
on it so that everybody may participate
in it a conspiracy where nobody is less
out a conspiracy in which everybody
participates a conspiracy from which
everybody potentially can benefit a
transparent conspiracy is this an
oxymoron secret conspiracies and open
conspiracies openly conspiring towards
the greater good openly conspiring
towards the lesser good Scientology
[Music]
anti-abortion Catholic mega churches the
conspiracies are so often born of
distrust I do not trust the story I was
told therefore i seek alternative
narratives oh look there's an
alternative narrative i will adopt that
because i don't believe the one that
i've told because i don't trust them
there's something about conspiracies
abounding when narratives are not
trusted justified paranoia being
continually lied to damaging one's
capability to differentiate between
truth and lie becoming confused at what
is the truth because there's been so
undermined
but one can no longer distinguish black
and white it's a it's a deep deep
betrayal when those upon whom you have
relied to tell you the truth when you
discover that they have not been telling
you the truth
this is a profound betrayal and must be
psychologically very traumatic and in
times of trauma one grabs for things
which will give them comfort even if
they are not actually nurturing or
helpful mine's broken by the trauma
induced by the divine mother and father
neglecting exploiting the divine child
to feed their own hunger divine parents
as hungry ghosts devouring their own
children to satisfy the lust and the
hunger which can never be satisfied
descending to the ultimate depth of
devouring the child which was destined
to become the divine parent destroying
the cycle of life